Finding aid to the Letty Cottin Pogrebin papers SSC.MS.00294
Sophia Smith Collection
Letty Cottin Pogrebin papers
1955-2011
Sophia Smith Collection
Pogrebin, Letty Cottin
SSC.MS.00294
100 linear feet (100 boxes)
Journalist; co-founder, National Women's Political Caucus; co-founder, Ms. magazine; editor; Feminist. The collection consists largely of Pogrebin's professional papers reflecting her career as a writer and journalist, as well as her social activism in the Women's Liberation and feminist movements. The collection is organized primarily by writing and other projects and includes correspondence; research, organization, and subject files; drafts, published writings, and speeches interspersed throughout. There is a small amount of biographical material and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access:
Files pertaining to Pogrebin's consciousness raising group "Next Step Women" are closed until January 1, 2050 or Pogrebin's death, whichever comes first.
Financial information is closed until January 1, 2020 or Pogreben's death, whichever comes first.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Letty Pogrebin began donating her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1986 and has made regular additions to the collection since then. Accesion Numbers not listed in this archive include 86S-40, 86S-68, 87S-6, 87S-61, 87S-63, 87S-89, 88S-51, 88S-74, 89S-10, 90S-34, 90S-46, 91S-61, 92S-24, 92S-42, 92S-49, 93S-25, 93S-68, 94S-19, 94S-53, 95S-10, 96S-01, 96S-14, and 96S-32.
Biographical / Historical
Born in New York City, 9 June 1939. Graduated from Brandeis University in 1959. She began her career in book publishing as an editorial assistant and director of publicity and subsidiary rights at the publishing house of Bernard Geis Associates. Her journalistic career has included freelance writing for the New York Times, TV Guide, Boardroom Reports, and Good Housekeeping, among others. She contributed "The Working Woman" column to Ladies' Home Journal from 1971 to 1981. A founder of Ms. magazine, she edited and contributed from its beginning. Pogrebin is the author of How to Make It in a Man's World (1970), Getting Yours (1975), Growing Up Free (1980), Family Politics (1983), Among Friends (1987), and Deborah, Golda and Me (1991). She is also editor of Stories for Free Children (1982), contributor to numerous anthologies, and a popular lecturer on non-sexist childrearing, family life, and feminism and Judaism. She was a founder of the National Women's Political Caucus and is an active member of many other organizations.
Other Finding Aids
This online finding aid currently provides detailed description of only the most recent additions to this collection. Additional materials are described in unpublished lists that can be sent to you upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.
Related Materials
See also: Associated materials can be found in the Gloria Steinem Papers; the records of Ms. Magazine and Ms. Foundation for Women; and an interview with Pogrebin in An Activist Life student oral history project.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists largely of Pogrebin's professional papers reflecting her career as a writer and journalist, as well as her social activism in the women's liberation and feminist movements. The collection is organized primarily by writing and other projects and includes correspondence; research, organization, and subject files; drafts, published writings, and speeches interspersed throughout. There is a small amount of biographical material and memorabilia.
Women -- China -- History -- Sources; Child rearing -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Feminism -- New York(State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Feminism -- Periodicals -- History -- 20th century; Feminism -- Political aspects -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Feminism -- Religious aspects -- Judaism -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Feminists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources; Jewish women -- United States -- Biography -- Sources; Journalists -- United States -- 20th century -- Biography -- Sources; Judaism -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Parenting -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Women -- Congresses; Steinem, Gloria; Ms. (periodical); Speeches; correspondence; Research; Organization files; Writings; Publications; Proofs; memorabilia; Business records; scrapbooks; Appointment books; Address books; Books; Brochures; clippings; Contracts; notebooks; Electronic mail; Fund raising; Galley proofs; lecture notes; Typescripts; Videotapes; Pamphlets; Audiotapes; Computer media; Pogrebin, Letty Cottin; Pogrebin, Letty Cottin
- Letty Cottin Pogrebin papers and t-shirts, 1989-2017; 2018-S-0031
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 3 contains financial information closed until 2020 at the donor's request.
  - "How to be a Friend to a Friend Who's Sick" (7 folders): correspondence re: book design, publicity, outreach, and audio book version, 2013 (Box 1)
  - "Tiny Letters" (LCP's email newsletter--2 folders), 2016-2017 (Box 1)
  - Women's March in DC, 2016-2017 (Box 1)
  - Judaism and Gender (5 folders), 1999-2015 (Box 1)
  - "The Women of the Wall (Israel)", 1989-2000 (Box 1)
  - Two political t-shirts and 1 tote bag, Approximately 2016 (Box 1)
  - Kate Millett Memorial Service Program, 9 November 2017 (Box 2)
  - Promotional cards for "Three Daughter" (2001) and "How to Be a Friend to a Friend Who's Sick" (2013 (Box 2)
  - Brandeis University's Women, Gender, and Sexuality Program, 2009-2016 (Box 2)
  - "Single Jewish Male Seeking Soulmate" email correspondence, publicity, interviews, and reviews (8 folders), 2015 (Box 2)
  - Two political t-shirts, including "Peace Now" in English, Hebrew and Arabic; and "I Was There January 21, 2017" (Box 2)
  - Lectures, including email correspondence, itineraries, and contracts (two folders)--CLOSED until 2020, 2015-2016; Per the donor's request, any materials containing financial information are closed until 2020 (Box 3)